"The Stranger I Met" Episode 5
《我遇见的陌生人》 第5集
(Wu Gang Dumu)
（吴刚杜姆）
(Kyung Gi Joo)
（京基珠）
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》
Two days before the first murder
第一起谋杀案发生前两天
One of the three suspects has been arrested
三名嫌疑人之一 已被逮捕
the other two
另外两个
Nothing special yet
还没有什么特别的
When everything is so chaotic
在一切都那么混乱的 时候
She is coming
她来了
He is the first victim of Wu Zongri's serial murder case
他是吴宗日连环杀人案的 第一个受害者
she
她
The teacher who will be with you throughout the month
整个月 都会陪伴你的老师
It’s teacher Li Zhouying
是李周英老师
- Seoul National University.. - Where..
- 首尔大学.. - 哪里..
- Major in Korean Literature - You must have read it
- 韩国文学专业 - 你一定看过
What's wrong?
怎么了？
I got a call from the principal
我接到校长的电话
I couldn’t make an appointment to meet with teacher Li Zhouying.
和李周英老师见面的预约 没能联系上
That's definitely what I know.
绝对是我所知道的情况
That day I chose her at first sight
那天我 第一眼就选择了她
as my beautiful first death
作为我美丽的第一次死亡
Will that girl die?
那个女孩会死吗？
how do you know?
你怎么知道？
This is a case that has not happened yet
这是一个尚未发生的案例
Now how do we know this?
现在我们怎么知道这里呢？
(Part 5 – A Confession)
（第五部分——一种忏悔）
what did you just say?
你刚刚说什么？
Article (5)
第(5)条
Isn't it a coincidence that we meet here ?
我们在这里相遇 ，难道不是巧合吗？
if all this is true
如果这一切都是真的
tonight
今晚
Well, two days before that school teacher died
那么，在那个学校老师去世的前 两天
He said there was a case where he suddenly disappeared
他说有一个他突然失踪的案例
Fortunately, I was discovered by the villagers.
幸好被村民 发现了
Because I know I've lost my way
因为我知道我迷失了方向
Although it was just a small incident in the end, in fact
虽然最后只是一个小事件， 但事实上
It seems like someone is being chased
好像有人被追赶
where was found
在哪里发现的
Do you know where it is?
你知道在哪里吗？
River bank
河岸
If it's close to a grocery store, it should be around here
如果靠近杂货店， 应该就在这附近
Well
唔
Li Zhuying
李柱英
-Teacher- No, I'm not
- 老师 - 不，我不是
ha
哈
What's your job?
你做什么工作？
Are you half crazy and want to die?
你是不是已经疯了一半，想死？
It’s Teacher Yin Hyejun again, is it you?
又是尹慧俊老师，是你吗？
ha
哈
Destroying it once is not enough
毁掉一次还不够
Do you want to destroy it two or three times again and again?
你想一次又一次地摧毁它两三次吗？
Gominsu was released, right?
Gominsu被释放了，对吗？
Why?
为什么？
Just followed the order
刚刚遵照命令
Very responsible words
很负责任的话
Because doing work this way
因为以这种方式做工作
This is a one-time error
这是一个一次性的错误
Now you have to accept this, Badang Badan
现在你必须接受这个， 巴东八探
if we are unlucky
如果我们不幸
Because of the person you released today
因为你今天释放的那个人
Someone's life may be in danger again
有人的生命 可能再次面临危险
Are you fat now?
你现在胖了吗？
It's just that guy again
只不过又是那个家伙
What did that guy do?
那家伙做了什么？
You have nothing to say, right?
你没什么可说的， 对吧？
I know for a fact that letting him go was the worst idea
我很清楚让他走是最糟糕的主意
Be sure to answer the question
一定要回答问题
- Gominsu Is it hot now? - I have no idea
- Gominsu 现在很热吗？ - 我不知道
i don't know what
我不知道什么
Who can do what?
谁能做什么？
Although you will know if you are caught
虽然你会知道你是否被抓住
Because alone, I don’t know anything anymore
因为一个人， 我已经什么都不知道了
if you knew anyway
如果你无论如何都知道的话
Although I don't want to share the responsibility of the police at all
虽然我根本不想分担警察的责任
So please let us not face each other again
所以请让 我们不要再面对面
road..
路..
Did it just disappear?
它就这样消失了吗？
I am..
我是..
Because I can't see much at night
因为晚上看不到太多东西
Too afraid of freedom
太害怕自由了
Free is not paranoid
免费并不偏执
anyone there?
有人吗？
Even ran away
甚至还逃跑了
I can't say I don't know anyone
我不能说我根本不知道有一个人
Is the stranger’s reaction calm?
陌生人的反应是不是 很平静？
Do not you remember?
你不记得了吗？
Regardless of whether I said it myself or not
不管是 不是我自己说的
-Teacher- No, I'm not
- 老师 - 不，我不是
why not?
为什么不？
Does anyone blame Mrs. Li ?
有人责怪李太太 吗？
The guy who ran away?
那个逃跑的家伙？
Do you know who that is?
你知道那是谁吗？
I do not know what to say
我不知道该说些什么
Ms. Li Zhuying
李珠英女士
Although I know it's hard to believe
虽然我知道这很难相信
I'm trying to help Ms. Li now
我现在正在努力帮助李女士
telling the truth can stop it
说实话可以阻止它
threatened by someone
被某人威胁
no matter what
不管是什么
everything must be said
一切都必须说
-Lee Joo -young- Worry
- 李柱英 - 担心
But thank you for your concern
不过还是谢谢你的关心
Really misunderstood
确实误会了
I'm treated like a human being
我被当作一个人对待
no threat
没有威胁
Relatives and elders will be worried
亲戚长辈会担心
Mr. Yin, can I come back?
尹先生，我可以回来吗？
Wait a moment
等一下
Come back for now
暂时回来吧
Yun Yang, let’s go too
云扬我们也走吧
Then see you at school tomorrow
那么明天在学校见
Stay safe now..
现在注意安全..
Can I buy you your favorite bread and feed it to you?
我买你最喜欢的面包喂你好吗？
What are bread skewers?
面包串是什么？
When you look at it, it's obvious that something is hidden
当你看它的时候，很明显有什么东西被隐藏了
Is it because of this release?
是因为这个发布吗？
If that person is two days older than that person
如果那个人比那个人多两天
I don't think he knew what was going to happen.
我认为他不知道会发生什么
Is this the home court?
这是主场吗？
(Tung Wah Tailor Shop)
(东华裁缝店)
(in front of the inn)
（客栈门口）
(Wujiang Hotel)
(吴江宾馆)
(hostel)
（旅馆）
Are you here to see Beijin come back?
你是来看贝金回来的吗？
I'm afraid there will be more questions that I don't know about
恐怕还会有更多我不知道的问题
Is it possible?
可以有吗？
For all I know, tonight probably won't happen again
据我所知，今晚 可能不会再发生了
I don't know if this is the right answer
我不知道这是否是正确的答案
Because I don't know what you know and what you don't know
因为我不知道你知道什么和不知道什么
That side might be the same
那一面可能是一样的
From now on we will learn about
从现在开始我们就来了解一下
Let's go to the right place to talk
我们去 正确的地方说话吧
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
The race tilts slightly to the right
比赛稍微向右倾斜
tilt in this direction
向这个方向倾斜
- Teacher, look - Gin Clan leans to the left
- 老师，你看 - Gin Clan 向左倾斜
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
Zuo Zuo
左左
left
左边
Last summer, he was struck down by lightning
去年夏天， 他被雷劈倒了
If you view the fix now
如果您现在查看修复程序
It's obvious that the owner doesn't care about the extent of his responsibility
很明显，店主 并不关心他的责任有多大
This is not a teahouse
这不是茶馆
You may already be familiar with this name
你可能已经熟悉这个名字
This is the birthplace of useless matchsticks
这里是无用火柴棍的 发源地
I got it
我得到了它
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
let's go now
现在我们走吧
I don't know if you already know, but this place
我不知道你是否已经知道，但是这个地方
In 1987, a serial murder case occurred in Wujiang
1987年，吴江 发生连环杀人案
You may have guessed it, but I'm following this case
你可能已经猜到了，但 我正在关注这个案例
Did the detective do it?
是侦探干的吗？
If you turn on the news, whether it's a weekend night or not
如果你打开新闻，无论是不是周末晚上
i think i remember
我想我记得
A criminal?
一名罪犯？
The person who showed the photo to Ekan's reporter ?
向Ekan的记者 展示照片的人？
Wouldn't it be more logical to assume he was a news anchor ?
假设他是新闻主播 不是更合逻辑吗？
Oh, like this
噢，就像这样
Nine people in the TV series
电视剧里的九个人
Sorry for not watching the news much
抱歉没怎么看新闻
Do you miss me too?
你也这么想我吗？
No, it's not like that
不，不是那样的
I thought about all kinds of things
我想过各种各样的事情
Even if I'm stuck in life, I want to be safe
即使我被生活困住，我也想安全
To get news?
为了得到消息？
Roughly speaking, it is like this
大致来说是这样的
When will the case be heard?
案件会在什么时候审理？
Two days later, on the 14th
两天后，即14日
Two days later on the 16th
两天后的16号
another case
另一个案例
A total of two girls died
共有两名女孩 丧生
- No. 20.. - One of them is missing
- 20号.. - 其中一人失踪
I left a message
我留言了
Although I thought I ran away from home
虽然我以为我离家出走了
actually dead
实际上已经死了
What do you say now?
你现在说什么？
because he is dead
因为他死了
There are three victims in total
受害人一共有三人
During more than thirty years
在长达三十多年的时间里
No clues were found, let alone a body.
没有找到任何线索，更不用说尸体了
Neither the police nor the victim’s family knew anything about it.
警方和受害人家属均不知情
How do you...
你怎么..
It's hard to believe but I'm here
很难相信，但我就在这里
I tell you as written here
我按照这里写的告诉你
(people I killed)
（我杀的人）
Please wait
请稍等
Wuwei wrote
五味写道
Madam, the article I wrote this time
女士，这次写的文章
Can't you give me a little taste?
你就不能给我一点味道吗？
Can we say a confession?
我们可以说是一种忏悔吗？
frank?
坦白？
thirty years ago
三十年前
The perfect crime someone committed
某人犯下的 完美犯罪
The person who starts the story is the protagonist
开启故事的人就是主角
Spend the rest of my life learning it alone
用我的余生独自了解它
Is it a pity?
可惜吗？
So thirty years ago
所以三十年前
I think it's about the same time as this novel.
我觉得和这本小说差不多是同时期的
(small door)
（小门）
This time let’s talk about myself seriously.
这次我们来认真谈谈我自己吧
just kidding
只是在开玩笑
It's all written there
都写在那里了
certainly
当然
The teacher is really
老师真是
I've been a teacher for a long time
我当老师已经很长时间了
Editor
责任编辑
National American Award?
国美奖？
Thanks to this, Wu Guang’s new novel has not yet been published
多亏了这一点， 五光的新小说尚未出版
i can hold
我能握住
Even though I completely forgot about it after I got here
尽管来到这里之后我就完全忘记了
After seeing that teacher just now
刚才 见到那位老师后
Like seeing something weird every now and then
就像时不时看到一些奇怪的东西
I read it again
我又读了一遍
Same as the content in the novel
和小说里的内容一样
I don't think this is about what really happened.
我不认为这是写真实发生过的事情
Anyway, that’s how it’s written
反正就是这样写的
Start with that school teacher
从那个学校老师开始
three girls died
三个女孩死了
I didn't find the real culprit until the end
直到最后我也没找到真正的罪魁祸首
This is about the real culprit, right?
这是关于真正的罪魁祸首吧？
Last paragraph of second page, last line
第二页最后一段 最后一行
please confirm
请确认
"The truth was never revealed."
“真相 最终没有被揭露。”
"He created all this death."
“他创造了所有这些死亡。”
I am who I am
我就是我
Even that fun fact
即使是那个有趣的事实
you are no longer in this house
你已经不在这所房子里了
really good
真的很好
(people I killed)
（我杀的人）
Is it really five lights?
真的是五光吗？
In fact, I didn't find the real culprit
事实上，我并没有找到真正的罪魁祸首
I'm surprised
我很惊讶
Although the defendant ultimately refused
尽管被告最终拒绝
reality is unknowable
现实是不可知的
Yes, that's why I talk like this
是的，这就是我这样说话的原因
The first time I stole it from my mother
第一次从妈妈那里偷来的
it's really about him
这真的是关于他的
If so, this may be new evidence
如果是这样，这可能是新的证据
can't say for sure
不能肯定地说
Anyway, this is a novel
无论如何，这是一本小说
Even though it's based on a true story
即使它是根据真实故事改编的
However, imagination can be very wild
然而，想象力 可以很天马行空
I started this week...
我是从这周开始的..
We cannot guarantee that this is a true representation of the Gowe Awards
我们不能保证这是五味奖的真实代表
I can't guarantee there won't be
我不能保证没有
Did you just see that?
你刚刚看到了吗？
I also wrote about the whereabouts of the missing teacher
我还写了失踪老师 的下落
someone who knows more than you
一个比你懂得更多的人
Isn't this the culprit?
这不是罪魁祸首吗？
Because they are from the same village
因为他们是同一个村子的
You can write down what you saw and heard at that time
可以写一下当时的 所见所闻
How many have I tried
我试了多少
Most are just official records
大多数只是官方记录
Why do you deny it?
你为什么要 否认呢？
Why do you make such clear accusations?
你为何提出如此明确的指控？
Do you want Wu Mei to be the culprit?
你想让五美成为罪魁祸首吗？
Why so much knowledge...
怎么这么多知识..
That's why I doubt
这就是我怀疑的原因
Five lights, I know
五光我知道
Because he is fully capable of doing so
因为他完全有能力这样做
What do you say now?
你现在说什么？
Are you talking about marrying me now?
你现在是在说要嫁给我吗？
pastor when
牧师何时
What happened again?
又发生什么事了？
What will you marry?
你会嫁给什么？
we are not together yet
我们还没有在一起
That guy who doesn't even taste like milk
那个连牛奶味都没有的家伙
This is why I made mistakes early on
这就是我早期犯下错误的原因
When will you actually be called out?
什么时候才真正被叫出来呢？
-This time- Yin Ying
- 这次 - 尹英
How is the child doing?
这孩子怎么样了？
Am I really going crazy because what did I do wrong?
我真的要发疯了，因为我做错了什么？
- I've never said anything like that - Ma'am.
- 我从来没有说过这样的话 - 女士
A son and a daughter will be born and they will live well
将会生下一个儿子和一个女儿， 他们会生活得很好
a son and a daughter
一个儿子和一个女儿
- Sun Al - How's it going?
- 孙阿尔 - 怎么样？
Is there something wrong with your ears?
你的耳朵有问题吗？
When did I say they would leave?
我什么时候 说过他们会走？
I just said I wanted to stay
我只是说我想留下来
I asked what the dream was.
我问梦想是什么。
I also want to have a family
我也想有一个家庭
Sorry, I already have a partner
抱歉，我已经有伙伴了
That’s why I can’t accept Hisoka’s heart
所以我无法接受希索的心
- what is
- 什么是
Even if not, there will be a time when I can meet in front of you
就算不是，我也有一段时间 能在这面前见面了
Hey
嘿
It's really that person
真的是那个人
Sun Ai's boyfriend?
孙爱的男朋友？
first love
初恋
Indeed, I came to speak
确实，我是来说话的
That's it
就是这样了
i hate flowers
我讨厌花
keep great
保持良好
(Bom Bom Theater)
（Bom Bom 剧场）
Sun E
孙鄂
I guess I should explain what I just saw
我想我应该解释一下我刚刚看到的
Need to explain slowly
需要慢慢解释
Unless it's not...
除非不是..
family?
家庭？
I have a son and a daughter
我有一个儿子 和一个女儿
I think this is my daughter's place
我认为这是我女儿的地方
Are you the daughter of suspect Bays?
你是嫌疑人巴伊斯的女儿吗？
bamboo
竹子
I'm scared
我很害怕
(hostel)
（旅馆）
How to call the police?
怎么报警？
Nothing to do with the police
与警察无关
I don't think I can stay here too long
我想我不能在这里呆太久
Excellent
出色地
Who really knows me?
谁真正了解我？
Ok, I know
嗯，我知道
(Someone is watching you)
（有人在看着你）
Are you too confused?
你也太迷茫了吧？
I was really shocked
我真的吓了一跳
It's hard to believe it's been thirty years since I was hit by a car
很难相信我被车撞已经三十年了
The person who hits someone is a time traveler
打人的人是时间旅行者
In front of that man’s house, my mother’s family was all seated
那个男人家门前，我妈一家人都 坐满了
bamboo
竹子
Why do you really want to go to school?
你为什么真的要去上学？
No
不
Why did you do that in the teahouse ?
你为什么在茶馆 这么做？
it's a bit complicated
这有点复杂
To separate my parents in the teahouse
是为了在茶馆里分开我的父母
What will be divided?
会划分什么？
Don't let mom and dad see each other
不要让爸爸妈妈看见对方
from the sun...
从太阳..
- Acres? - What?
- 英亩？ - 什么？
Yes, everything is accidental
是的，一切都是偶然
I remember getting hit by a car without thinking twice.
我记得我没有多想就被车撞了
Stay in front of young parents
留在年轻父母眼前
Should I consider separating the two?
我应该考虑将两者分开吗？
Have you never thought about the consequences of this?
你就没有想过这会带来什么样的结果吗？
- You can't come... - What's the matter?
- 你不能来.. - 什么事？
what happened
发生了什么
What happened to those little guys?
那些小家伙怎么了？
Do I know nothing about this?
我对此一无所知吗？
One small action can change someone's entire future
一个小小的行动 可以改变他人的整个未来
Did you tell me when you first came here ?
你第一天来这里的时候 有告诉我吗？
So what is it?
那么它是什么？
before coming here
来这里之前
I asked him what he was doing by the river
我问他在河边做什么
(police)
（警察）
That day at the river
那天在河边
Mother abandoned us and left
母亲抛弃了我们 离开了
no right to resent
没有权利怨恨
I abandoned my mother first
我先抛弃了我的母亲
because we don't know
因为我们不知道
I gave crazy love that I can't repay
我疯狂地 付出了无法回报的爱
(Suen Er)
（苏恩埃尔）
It's becoming a name that's crazy to ignore
它正在成为一个可以疯狂忽略的名字
one day suddenly
有一天突然
I don’t know if my mother understands
不知道妈妈是否明白
There are too many moments that I can't look back on
有太多的瞬间无法回头
it's too late
已经太迟了
That day, by the river, I had a strong desire
那天，在河边， 我有一种强烈的渴望
If there is only one chance
如果机会只有一次
It would be nice if I could look back for a moment
如果能有片刻 回头该多好
I don't know if I look crazy
我不知道我看起来是不是疯了
But actually, no matter what I do
但实际上， 无论我做什么
Until my mother went to the river
直到我妈妈去了那条河
If I think there's nothing I can do, I...
如果我认为我无能为力， 我...
I don't think I can bear it anyway
我想我无论如何都无法承受
Sorry, I didn't mean to say that
抱歉，我不是故意说这样的话
Come in
进来
Just listen to it today
今天听听就好了
Excellent
出色地
I have to ask this
我得问一下这个
Unless it's not
除非不是
That day at the river
那天在河边
Mother abandoned us and left
母亲抛弃了我们 离开了
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
I don't think I picked this up
我不认为这是我捡到的
(Women who study are more dangerous)
（读书的女人更危险）
Really when and where?
真的是什么时候、什么地点？
I stumbled upon this floating village on the banks of a river
我无意中发现了这个漂浮在河岸上的村庄
pick it up without thinking
不假思索地拿起它
Why?
为什么会有？
( Suspect in Wu Jong-il serial murder case )
（吴宗日连环杀人案 嫌疑人）
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
Where did it come from?
它从哪里来的？
There's something you need to know
有件事需要知道
(Wuzhengli Fishing Ground)
(五正里钓鱼场)
Because of what I said yesterday
因为我昨天说过的话
Don't worry
不用担心
This is my personal matter
这是我个人的事
Don't interfere with the work there
不干涉那边的工作
For me, my mother is...
对于我来说，妈妈是..
This is not a serious problem
这不是一个严重的问题
He gave birth to me but never looked up
他生下我却从未抬头
Because the one who ran away was my mother
因为逃跑的人是我妈妈
I don't quite understand how my mother feels
我不太了解妈妈的感受
As others have said, is there anything special and hurtful about it?
正如其他人所说， 有什么特别的和伤人的吗？
i don't even know
我什至不知道
I never knew or didn't want to know
我从来不知道或不想知道
But no matter who
但无论是谁
I know the one I love has no reason, I don't know what it feels like
我知道所爱的人没有理由 不知道那种感觉
i don't care what happens
我不在乎发生什么
The heart that misses my mother
那颗思念我母亲的心
Do you think your mother is not sensible enough?
你觉得你妈妈还不够懂事吗？
what does that mean..
这意味着什么..
Knowing this, would you still make such a choice?
知道这一点你还会做出这样的选择吗？
- What do you want to say now? - Listen carefully.
- 现在你想说什么 - 仔细听
First murder tomorrow night
明晚第一起谋杀案
You know stuff will come out
你知道东西会出来的
matchbox
火柴盒
and the memorandum therein
以及其中的备忘录
(Women who study are more dangerous)
（读书的女人更危险）
this..
这..
At that time, the police deliberately left the matter to the defendant
当时警方故意将此事留给被告人
They considered this mark
他们考虑了这个标记
Among the second victim’s belongings
第二名受害者的财物中
Because the same product comes out
因为同样的产品出来了
Is that the mark?
是那个标记吗？
So why is this...
那么这是为什么..
Why did the defendant use material from 34 years ago...
为什么被告使用的材料是34年前..
Will we meet again in 2021?
2021年我们还会再见面吗？
This is a popular store
这是一家热门商店
Why on the bank of the river where your mother died?
为什么会在你母亲去世的河岸边？
Unless it's not...
除非不是..
no definite evidence
没有确切的证据
Yes, your feelings are genuine
是的，你的感情是真诚的
Maybe your mother doesn't know
也许你妈妈不知道
but if
但如果
if it's true
如果是真的的话
That day, by the river, your mother...
那天，在河边，你的母亲..
if you meet someone else
如果你遇见了别人
That was 34 years ago
那是34年前的事了
If the real culprit
如果真正的罪魁祸首
So now you've made a mistake
所以现在你犯了一个错误
Do you hate yourself for giving up?
你是否恨自己 放弃了？
The person who can finally save my mother
最终能拯救我母亲的人
do not you?
你不是吗？
Yun Yang
云扬
Were you too scared yesterday?
昨天是不是太害怕了？
sorry
对不起
I lied to you on purpose
我故意对你撒谎
Basisu, it’s not just to meet that person.
巴希苏 根本不是为了遇见那个人
Yes
是的
Why did you miss this?
你为什么错过这个？
Until she becomes a gray-haired grandma
直到她成为白发苍苍的奶奶
I want to play with Yoongi forever
我想永远和玧其一起玩
dear mother
亲爱的妈妈
This is a letter, not a will
这是一封信，不是遗嘱
I will always be by your side
我会永远在你身边
My mom is always like this. .
我妈妈总是这样。。
I just promised
我刚刚答应过
How could it be misunderstood like this?
怎么会被人误解成这样呢？
how so..
为何如此..
Don't you understand in the end?
到最后你还不明白吗？
Yun Yang
云扬
Is that disappointment?
那是失望吗？
sorry
对不起
What is always so painful?
什么事总是那么痛苦？
I do not understand
我不明白
No, I really don't know either
不， 我真的也不知道
It was written on a piece of paper taken from a matchbox
它是从火柴盒中取出的一张纸写成的
They will have a common encounter
他们将有共同的相遇
Don't worry
不用担心
more..
更多的..
Another such tragedy
又一个这样的悲剧
I will protect it from happening
我会保护它不发生
I will protect you no matter what
无论如何我都会保护你
But thanks anyway
不过还是谢谢
Is it that bad?
有那么糟糕吗？
Can't we have a cold drink together?
就不能一起喝杯冷饮吗？
I didn't marry Fan Feng
我没有和范奉结婚
Genlai, what are they doing?
根莱，他们在做什么？
I have no idea
我不知道
I heard that the level was released, has Sun E's level dropped a lot?
听说等级出了， 孙娥的等级是不是下降了很多？
- Thank you - Yes, do your job
- 谢谢 - 是的，尽你的职责
- Teacher Che- Yes
- 车老师 - 是的
Take it and eat it
拿过来吃吧
- I'll eat well. - Okay.
- 我会吃得好 - 好吧
- Yes , this is...
- 对 ，这就是..
- Our son sent it from the United States.
- 是的 - 我们的儿子从美国寄来的
Oh America?
噢美国？
Doesn't it look great?
看起来不是很好吗？
- This is... - Ha
- 这是.. - 哈
I don’t know if it’s American, but something seems wrong.
不知道是不是美国的， 好像有点不对劲
- Did you notice? - Thanks
- 你注意到了吗？ - 谢谢
So now you've made a mistake
所以现在你犯了一个错误
Did you hate yourself and give up?
你是否厌恶自己并 放弃了？
Mother
母亲
good mom
好妈妈
No need to say it so strongly
没必要说那么强烈
I need to say something sweet.
我得说一点甜言蜜语
- Yes - Indeed, this country is huge
- 是的 - 确实，这个国家很大
The country is big and the flowers are also big
国家很大， 花也很大
- The leaves are also big, very good - Yes
- 叶子也很大，很好 - 是的
- Hello - Yes, are you here?
- 你好 - 是的，你到了吗？
I think so
我也这么认为
It's time to throw this away
到了该扔掉这个的时候
Why throw it away?
为什么要扔掉它？
Teacher Li Zhouying is here
李周英老师来了
14 hours flight to South Korea
14小时飞往韩国的航班
Come on, cause I'll give you precious jelly
快点吧，因为我会给你珍贵的果冻
Yes
是的
I didn't tell anyone about last night
我没有告诉任何人昨晚的事
Go get it for me
去帮我拿一下
gentlemen
先生
Jelly from America
来自美国的果冻
i will bring it
我会带来它
Thanks
谢谢
- Is it sweet? - come from America
- 甜吗？ - 来自美国
come on now
现在来吧
- try this - thanks
- 试试这个 - 谢谢
- I'm depressed - I'm still the same
- 我很沮丧 - 我还是一样
- I think I'm going to get fat - Am I a bitch?
- 我想我会变胖 - 我是个婊子吗？
I answered a lot
我回答了很多
(Intermediate Lee Sun El, advanced class Gomizu)
（中级 Lee Sun El，高级班Gomizu）
- I can't believe it - I guess
- 我不敢相信 - 我猜
step 1
步骤1
- Level 1 - His level is the same as before
- 一级 - 他的等级与以前相同
I'm going back to class
我要回去上课了
- That's great. - Ma'am.
- 太棒了 - 女士
divine water
神的水
Is this enough?
这够了吗？
I am proud of you
我以你为荣
How to get level?
如何获得等级？
- School-wide level 1 - Ms.
- 全校一级 - 女士
The whole school is Level 1
整个学校都是一级
- Step 1 - Bamboo
- 第一步 - 竹子
- We are upgrading hahaha
- 我们正在升级 哈哈哈
First level in the school
全校一级
I guessed most of it
我猜到了大部分
hehe
呵呵
Is it level one?
是一级吗？
I will be sad
我会伤心的
I'm very proud
我很骄傲
Really?
真的吗？
Can you live with sad bad people?
你能和悲伤的坏人一起生活吗？
he came out
他出来了
Pretend you can't pass the exam
假装无法通过考试
Lee Seung-il always behaves like this
李升尔的举动总是这样
Are you that happy?
你有那么高兴吗？
Everyone can see it on the forehead
额头上所有人都看得到
Should I post it?
我要贴一下吗？
- Are you crazy? - Yin Ying
- 你疯了吗？ - 尹英
This crazy Kim Hye Kyun
这个疯狂的金惠均
- Hey, you're in trouble. - Come on.
- 嘿，你有麻烦了 - 快点
Qingxian
庆贤
Won't you come back soon?
你不快点回来吗？
- I hate it - I'm disappointed
- 我讨厌它 - 我很失望
- how is he? - cool
- 他怎么样？ - 酷
- let's go - very disappointed
-我们走吧 -非常失望
bring back
带回来
(school rules)
（校规）
This school is weird
这所学校很奇怪
it only sticks to the sides
它只粘在侧面
Do you like such a man?
你喜欢这样的男人吗？
What do you really like to watch?
你真正喜欢看什么？
(College Entrance Examination Part 1)
（高考第一部分）
This mathematical description can be used like this
这个数学描述可以这样使用
Interesting
很有意思
The whole school is suspicious
整个学校都怀疑
Please be conscious
请自觉
Mother
母亲
He is indeed a poor man
他确实是个可怜人
How is it going?
最近好吗？
nothing
没什么
very good
很好
I don't want to lose my friendship
我不想失去我的友谊
Unless it's not...
除非不是..
Did something go wrong yesterday?
昨天的问题是不是出了问题？
Even the flowers I gave you don’t work?
连我送你的花都不管用吗？
what is that?
那是什么？
Why go through the trouble of choosing one yourself?
为什么要费劲 自己去挑选呢？
The one I bought is more beautiful
我买的更漂亮
indeed
确实是
take it
拿着它
Girls don't like it very much because it's naive
女孩 不太喜欢它，因为它很天真
is that so?
是这样吗？
so
所以
Who will open it?
谁来打开？
Are you really not going to tell me?
真的不告诉我吗？
Hey, that's it...
嘿嘿就是这样..
I'll tell you if I can
如果可以的话我会告诉你
I know, try it
我知道了，试试吧
Thanks
谢谢
- Tried it with Su Shui - Yeah
- 和苏水试过了 - 嗯
He said it was a flower
他说这是一朵花
Your ho...what?
你的豪..什么？
Do girls like it?
女孩喜欢吗？
I'm sure
我敢肯定
Although he says he doesn't always like it
尽管他说他并不总是喜欢这样
This is what it means to like
这就是喜欢的意思
pretend to be shy
假装害羞
If you don’t like it, you just don’t like it. Why do you feel ashamed?
不喜欢就是不喜欢， 为什么觉得羞耻呢？
Hey, so just give me a flower
嘿，所以你就送我一朵花吧
Give me a flower, where is the rest?
给我一朵花， 剩下的在哪里？
Oh, is that right?
噢，是这样吗？
Well, that too. .
嗯，那也是。。
I use it in a good place
我用在一个好地方
Hello
你好
Why do you think this is not Gotsu?
为什么你认为这不是五津？
If this place is the culprit
如果这个地方是罪魁祸首
34 years later, another murder
34年后，又一起谋杀案
This is why my mother died
这就是我母亲去世的原因
I think the defendant may be more of a backlighter
我认为被告可能更多的是后光
It's entirely possible
这是完全有可能的
but..
但..
The man who chased the school teacher and ran away last night
昨晚 追学校老师然后逃跑的那个人
Who is the one?
会是谁呢？
I think this is the one I've been waiting for
我想这就是我一直在等待的人
at the same time
同时
I thought there would be answers on Lee Joo Young's path and waited
我以为在李柱英的道路上会有答案并 等待
Lee Joo Young’s route on the night he was killed
李柱英被杀当晚的路线
(Let us move forward with freedom, creativity and wisdom)
（让我们带着自由、创造力 、智慧前行）
The person who got off work that night was Lee Joo-young
那天晚上下班的人是李周英
I left school around ten o'clock
我十点左右离开学校
(Wuzhong Middle School)
(吴忠中学)
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
destination..
目的地..
This is the Bom Bom teahouse we went to yesterday
这就是我们昨天去的 Bom Bom 茶馆
welcome
欢迎
There are twenty minutes and half past ten
其中有二十分钟和 十点半
Lee Joo Young is out
李珠英出来了
The next destination is definitely Wuzheng Inn
下一个目的地肯定 是五正客栈
But that night, I couldn't go to Lee Joo Young's hotel
但那天晚上， 我没能去李柱英的旅馆
(pay phone)
（付费电话）
(Wujiang Hotel)
(吴江宾馆)
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
From teahouse to hotel , even if it’s a step slower
从茶馆到宾馆 哪怕是慢一步
only thirty minutes
仅三十分钟
Just disappeared in such a short distance
就在那么短的距离内消失了
Until he was found dead the next day
直到第二天他被发现成了尸体
Are there no witnesses within such a short distance ?
这么短的距离内 没有目击者吗？
No one saw who he met at the same time
没有人看到他同时遇到了谁
That's why I didn't watch it myself
这就是为什么我自己没看
Same time and same place
同一时间同一地点
towards one direction
朝一个方向
Because I will stand behind Lee Joo Young
因为我会站在李周英的身后
So maybe we'll see the man in the blue hat again
所以也许我们会再次见到那个戴蓝帽子的 人
Blue hat?
蓝色帽子？
Lee Joo Young’s 20 Minutes in the Teahouse
李周英在茶馆的 20分钟
He was the only person I met there
他是我在那里遇到的唯一一个人
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
Is this an argument?
这是一场争论吗？
Although he is a very suspicious person
虽然是一个非常可疑的人
At that time, the police were unable to fully investigate who it was.
当时警方无法全面调查到底是谁
But the guy I chased last night was wearing a blue hat
但我昨晚追的那个人 戴着蓝色帽子
The National American Awards have not been completely cancelled.
国美奖并未完全取消
will be fully considered and monitored
将得到充分考虑和监测
but..
但..
As for Gomisu, I still need it
至于Gomisu，我还是需要它
I'll catch Mion carefully here
我会在这里小心地 抓住米昂
1987 and 2021
1987年和2021年
That man can't kill anyone
那个人不能杀死任何人
Because I'm here to do this
因为我是来这样做的
So please trust me and wait
所以请相信我并 等待
Miss Yu Fan
余范小姐
(Confident freedom)
（自信的自由）
(Let us unite as one nation through cooperation)
（让我们通过合作团结为一个国家）
I'll come back to make sure it's safe
我会回来确认是否安全
Shall we go together?
我们一起去吗？
The work I have to do is neither ordinary nor special.
我要做的工作 不一般也不特殊
and then
进而
Don't go alone, go with your mom and uncle
不要一个人去， 跟妈妈和叔叔一起去
(Cream Twisted Jelly)
（奶油扭纹果冻）
Let's go with Yoon Young
和尹英一起去吧
american jelly
美国果冻
(Detective Division 1)
（侦探一科）
misunderstanding
误解
I was not chased or threatened by anyone
我没有被任何人追赶或 威胁
They must be hiding something
他们肯定在隐瞒什么
Are you going to buy your favorite rolls?
你要买你最喜欢的面包卷吗？
I know I'm following
我知道我在追随
I let myself hear these words on purpose
我故意让自己听到这些话
It seems to be telling the woman that she is in a dangerous situation
仿佛在告知女子身处危险境地
Yes
是的
Brother, where are you going?
大哥你要去哪儿？
- Not that bad - So why eat them all?
- 没那么糟糕 - 那么为什么要全部吃掉呢？
Hey badminton number eight
嘿羽毛球八号
Where are you going alone?
你一个人要去哪里？
(Wujiang Police Station)
（吴江派出所）
confirm
确认
Why not reconfirm?
为什么不重新确认？
Like the hospital manager again, he broke the pot
又像医院经理一样，打破了锅
If you didn't bring it
如果没有带的话
Please stop, eight hundred knees
请停下来，八百膝盖
Yes, there is a new teacher at Goi High School
是的，五井高中 来了一位新老师
Things are a little weird, so I'll be back
情况有点奇怪，所以 我会回来的
Hey
嘿
What's weird?
有什么奇怪的？
Don’t you know who the eldest brother is?
不知道大哥是谁吗？
(in front of the inn)
（客栈门口）
(Wuzhong Hotel)
(吴中宾馆)
That school teacher has three old crimes
那个学校老师 有三桩旧罪
We just pretend not to know
我们只是假装不知道
He said he was not an ordinary person
他说他不是一个普通人
Tonight
今晚了
If nothing else changes, tonight
如果没有其他变化的话 就是今晚
Is it really not helpful?
真的没有帮助吗？
Since it's my business, I can do anything
既然是我的事， 我可以做任何事
Because I'm used to moving alone
因为我习惯一个人搬家
What if something changes?
如果有变化怎么办？
Go first
先走
- Hello
- 你好 你好
- Hello yes
- 是的
business card
名片
- take a look - hello
- 看看 - 你好
How is this going?
这是怎么回事？
- Hello - Yeah
- 嗯
- Hello
- 你好 你好
I asked what happened
我问怎么了
I'm talking about removing it
我正在谈论删除它
Make sure you work hard for about a month
确保认真工作还剩一个月左右
The opportunity has been given
机会已经给了
Aren’t you here to help Li Zhouying?
你不是来帮助李周英的吗？
For such people, you have to help, right?
对于这样的人，你必须去帮助，对吗？
I?
我？
Mr. Yin Haijun
尹海俊先生
You might even die because of that woman
你甚至可能会因为那个女人而死
do you know?
你知道吗？
Hey, let's go grab it, don't miss it
嘿，我们去抓住它吧， 别错过了
- Yes, let's go.
- 是的，我们走
ha
哈
leg
腿
Why so fast?
为什么这么快？
tired
疲劳的
If I really only paid 500,000 won, I would ask a Korean lady to do it
如果我真的只付50万韩元， 我会请韩国小姐做
They said it belonged to my father
他们说这是我父亲的
strength..
力量..
There will only be half a million
只会有五十万
Even if you give five million, it is absolutely impossible
就算给五百万也是绝对不可能的
Korean wife, that little girl
韩国太太，那个小女孩
My daughter, what is going on?
我的女儿，这是怎么回事？
Father
父亲
The daughter is Yu Zaili’s Genshun
女儿是禹在里的根顺
Is it the same now?
现在也一样吗？
what happened
发生了什么
Even Chestnut smiled, poor child
就连栗子也笑了，可怜的孩子
really annoyed
真的很恼火
- Mom - I'm going to Seoul
- 妈妈 - 我要去首尔
When is the fastest bus?
最快的公交车是什么时候？
I was shocked
我吓了一跳
Will be there in five minutes
五分钟后就会到
- Give me a ticket. - A ticket?
- 给我一张票 - 一张票？
Wait a moment
等一下
- Ha - let's see.
- 哈 - 让我们看看
Give it quickly
快点给
Why are they all running around sweating ?
为什么他们都满头大汗地 跑来跑去？
What
什么
- Ha - Wait a minute, teacher.
- 哈 - 等一下，老师
arrest him
逮捕他
Where does the otter come from to give the orders?
水獭在哪里来发号施令？
- Ah Nuttle - But I listen
- 啊纳特尔 - 但我听
-let go
- 松手
let it go
放手吧
-Miss -Teacher
- 小姐 - 老师
- Let go - just for a moment
- 放手 - 就一会儿
-Teacher, wait a minute - let go
-老师，等一下 -放手
please
请
I don't know why I do this
我不知道我为什么要这样做
I have to stay here tonight
今晚我必须留在这里
Only then can you catch it
只有这样你才能抓住它
It will be like this
会是这样的
Korean teachers also came
韩国老师也来了
Mother
母亲
- You two - Lee Joo Young
- 你们两个 - 李柱英
Do you think I don't know you are watching me every night?
你以为我不知道你每天晚上都在看着我吗？
That night he found me under the bridge
那天晚上他在桥下 找到了我
Isn't it a coincidence?
难道不是巧合吗？
hand it over to the police
交给警方
It was planned from the beginning
从一开始就计划好了
Now I misunderstood something
现在我误解了一些事情
Please calm down and give me that knife
请冷静下来， 把那把刀给我
i don't trust anyone
我不相信任何人
dirty spy
肮脏的间谍
please believe my words
请相信我的话
us..
我们..
I'm doing this to help Lee Joo Young
我这样做是为了帮助李柱英
What's the matter, ma'am?
什么事，女士？
release
发布
please lee juyoung
请李周英
Please raise your voice because the police are coming
请提高声音，因为警察来了
Is there no place to hide, father?
难道没有地方可以躲吗，父亲？
here, here, inside
这里，这里，里面
go in
进去
How are you? No injuries?
你还好吗？ 没有受伤吗？
I am fine
我很好
Yes
是的
i don't know how to speak
我不知道如何说话
The bus has left. Who are you talking about?
公共汽车已经开走了， 你在说谁？
We here have been talking about Miss Korea
我们这里一直在 谈论韩国小姐
Hello
你好
You said it's impossible, you bad guy
你说这不可能， 你这个坏蛋
The father said, my daughter is Oh Jae-ri Geun-soon
父亲说，我的女儿是吴在里根顺
Let’s check the accommodation again
我们再检查一下住宿情况
- Pastor Yes - Yes, I know.
- 牧师 是的 - 是的，我知道
- Ha - A gift from my father, bad girl.
- 哈 - 我父亲送的东西，坏女孩
Why..
为什么..
all because of me
都是因为我
I misjudged the changes
我错误地判断了 变化
In any case, it would be too risky to send him back to the inn tonight.
不管怎样，今晚送他回客栈太冒险了
Yes, take them to a safe place first
是的，首先带他们到安全的地方
I thought I was alone
我以为我是一个人
I'm scared
我很害怕
sorry
对不起
Is it really okay to go alone?
一个人去真的好吗？
Just look at this face and I'll be back
只要看看这张脸我就会回来
(Bom Bom Tea House Coffee and Tea)
（Bom Bom茶馆咖啡和茶）
if you are lucky
如果你幸运的话
Even without Lee Joo Young
即使没有李柱英
at the same time and the same place
在同一时间同一地点
I wonder if that person will come out
不知道那个人会不会出来
if you are lucky
如果你幸运的话
that face
那张脸
Continue to confirm
继续确认
that person..
那个人..
Because 34 years later, I will be the one responsible for killing my mother.
因为34年后，我将成为杀害我母亲的罪魁祸首
Going crazy
快要疯了
(Women who study are more dangerous)
（读书的女人更危险）
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》
one of the three suspects
三名嫌疑人之一
hidden blue hat
隐藏的蓝帽子
Everything matches the action
一切都与动作相匹配
The most likely culprit is Bakhisu
最有可能的罪魁祸首是Bakhisu
If the blue hats are the real culprits
如果蓝帽子才是真正的罪魁祸首
His mother...
他的母亲..
i killed my wife
我杀了我的妻子
The blue hat is yours...
蓝帽子是你的..
I know, I saw it with my own eyes
我知道， 我亲眼所见
Although I never thought of becoming such a person
虽然我从来没有想过成为这样的人
just be one of the skeptics
只是成为怀疑论者之一
Is the blue hat talking about my father now?
蓝帽子现在说的是我父亲吗？
what happened
发生了什么
impossible
不可能的
(appendix)
（附录）
How to do this...
这个怎么做..
how..
如何..
This kind of action has been done before
这种动作已经做过了
stay away
别靠近
(Bangbang Teahouse)
（邦邦茶馆）
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》